The following is a presentation of the
Arizona Cardinals Broadcast Network.
Coming up on Cardinals Bird Watch. Free
agency is moving fast and Paul and Danny
break down what it means for the roster.
Danny sits down one-on-one with new
running back Tyler Allgeier fresh off
signing with the team and with new faces
arriving, opportunity is knocking in
Arizona. Cardinals Bird Watch starts
right now presented by SeatGeek. All
right, I don't know what the question is
right off the top but I do know, yes, we
are dealing with the hottest March in
Phoenix history. Just don't blame NFL
free agency.
>> those dollar signs with the new deals
that are raising the temps as we welcome
you into Cardinals Bird Watch. Paul
Calvisi, Danny Sorensen. It's
construction season in the NFL. This
month is the wave of free agency, next
month it's the draft.
>> the helmets for hard hats here as teams
build, right? And for the Cardinals from
the inside out, the trenches. Yeah, the
Cardinals have signed some veteran
offensive lineman. Arguably the biggest
signings have been to the big guys on
the offensive line. They brought in
veteran tackles Elijah Wilkinson who
started all 17 games with Atlanta last
year and Matt Prior.
>> And then a big catch, a reported 30
million plus to Steelers left guard
Isaac Seumalo, right? And we asked him
in our meet and greet, what's it like
just to play the position itself,
interior offensive line?
Offensive line is very similar, I would
think like corner. Right, you could have
65 great reps but that one rep that's
not so great is what will be focused on
versus you play D-line or receiver, you
get one really good play a game and
you're you're an All-Pro. It's an apt
analogy. One bad play and that's all
anybody seems to remember. Seumalo is
the projected starter at left guard
though he does enter training camp in a
battle for best hair and not just with
you, Paul.
>> buzzer just went off on that. No, we're
talking about Andrew Winger, new guy,
we'll get to him in a little bit and the
return of Roy Lopez, fan favorite,
valley native and you know Roy means
business when he comes in rocking the
black cowboy hat. He rocked it pretty
well. He was on Cardinals Cover 2 with
Craig Greuel and yourself and answered a
question about the dirty work he does as
a nose tackle. It's uh it's a world that
I like to live in. It's a it's a
mentality I like to live in. It's a it's
a world and mentality that I was raised
on and um
you know, you go back to the sport of
wrestling, it's all it's all in it it's
all in the hips, it's all in your hands.
Inside hands, low man wins, it's it's
something that's been preached to me
since I was in diapers, man. All right,
there you go. Roy Lopez back in black
after a year in Detroit and then the
Cardinals also add another nose tackle
body type, 340 lb Andrew Billings from
the Bears.
>> They added a couple of players on
defense. They signed linebacker Zach
Allen to a two-year deal. He was most
recently with New England and started in
the Super Bowl for the Patriots.
>> And with Jalen Thompson going to Dallas,
well, here comes a high energy, hard
hitting safety, Andrew Winger from
Jacksonville and we asked him to
describe his style of play. Yeah, I
would say it's it's rugged. Um I love to
play kind of old school, do your job but
once you arrive, do it violently and do
it psychotically, kind of if you if you
will. So that's kind of going to be my
it'll probably be similar to Boo Buddha.
Just absolutely fly around, go 1,000
miles an hour and see what happens. So
but with a little bit of discipline
there to do your job.
>> the guy they call Doing. There you go,
the hair competition again with Winger.
And then let's see, who else, what else?
Well, Cardinals signed a two-time Pro
Bowl return man in Devin Duvernay.
>> They also signed a high energetic wide
receiver in Kendrick Bourne. The 10-year
veteran was most recently with the
Niners and once upon a time, Cardinals
head coach Mike LaFleur was Bourne's
position coach out in the Bay.
>> So we asked him for a scouting report on
the Cardinals new head coach.
>> What do you know about Mike LaFleur that
the rest of us are going to find out?
Mike has great energy. He he may not
show it all the time but like he is very
energetic. He he kind of got like Sean
McVay vibes.
>> know, he's going to be high energy,
passionate about the game. He knows how
to operate a team and I'm I'm excited to
see how it goes and uh he he's just a
special person to me. Still ahead. Danny
goes one-on-one with new running back
Tyler Allgeier. That's next on Cardinals
Bird Watch presented by SeatGeek.
Cardinals Bird Watch is sponsored by
State Farm. Like a good neighbor, State
Farm is there. Tyler Allgeier, fifth
round rookie, former linebacker.
What is playing linebacker do for you as
a running back? Um it for sure
give me a true understanding of how
defensive fits, like how like backers
fit, how to how to D-line fits and um
it really yeah, it really just fit like
fit in scheme. I think that played a big
role and then when I switched back, I
was like damn like like I'm dialed now.
Like I I I understand it. Like it really
clicked. All right, that is Tyler
Allgeier. Get to know him, right?
Although I think the Cardinals have a
pretty good sense, Danny. He went
against the Cardinals in '22 his rookie
year, again in '23, again last season.
Now plot twist, he'll be running the
ball for the Cardinals.
>> That's great news for the Cardinals.
Allgeier is one of the toughest tackles,
he's hard to stop. We did stop him long
enough though to have a chat with him
here in the studio to get to know the
newest running back in that Cardinals
room. Head coach Mike LaFleur will be
calling the offensive plays. What have
your early conversations with him been
like?
>> Yeah, no, it's been it's been good, man.
You know, he's excited, pumped up for me
to be here. Um
she was just a just an exciting offense
to be a part of. I think obviously he
came from the Rams so doing what they do
and how successful they were, just uh
bring it to Arizona so I think it should
be great. You're coming from Atlanta.
Falcons drafted you back in 2022. As a
rookie, you had a 1,000 yard rushing
season. 13 of your 18 career rushing
touchdowns have come inside the 10 and
I'm not saying this as a jinx but you
enter Arizona with zero career fumbles.
What style of play are you bringing to
the Cardinals?
>> And obviously tough physicality. Um
we've working on the speed so a little
little breakaway speed and stuff but I
think just physicality. I think James
does a great job as that as well so just
being able to tandem with him and uh and
Trey and Trey Benson so it should be it
should be really good. I think um
it should be it should be really good.
I'm excited for it.
>> You are joining a tough mentally and
physically running backs room with James
Conner and Trey Benson. What's the most
crucial aspect to have a running backs
room where everybody is complementing
each other? I think I should I think you
said you said it best, complementing
each other. I think all of us just
feeding off each other. Oh, one makes a
good run, okay, like who like who's
next? Like who's about to who and just
uh keeping that momentum, feeding off
each other and then just being just
being brothers and freaking competing
with each other. I think that's the
that's the biggest thing and just um
getting this team closer to victory so.
As you get settled into Arizona, place
you haven't spent a lot of time in
before, what do you like to do in your
free time? How are you going to get
settled here? Sure, I heard I think
golf's a big thing out here so so we're
about to dabble with some golf. You
know, I've been working on my swing a
little bit. We're okay. We're decent but
it should be yeah, it should be good.
>> There's a lot of players in that locker
room who are who are good golfers so I'm
sure they would teach you but they will
also I'm sure not go easy on you.
>> Yeah, not at all. Yeah, Collins already
told me that he was um
I think he shot like a 73 or something
like that. I was like damn, good for
you. I'm barely breaking 100 so
it's uh it's I I got some work to do. He
he doesn't really need to practice but I
got some work to do. What have those
conversations been like with your new
teammates as they welcome you to the
valley?
>> Uh he's been good, you know, just very
very welcoming and um she was just ready
to get to work. I think that's the
that's the biggest thing all around
around this building just uh
she just build just the building blocks
just 1% better every day. Well, Tyler,
as you uh get ready to get to work here
in Arizona, appreciate the time and
welcome to the valley. Oh, thank you.
Thanks for having me.
Let's go.
Look, I just love his backstory. He was
a walk-on at BYU, ended up a second team
All-American, fifth round rookie who
rushed for 1,000 yards his rookie
season.
>> A running backs room with Allgeier,
James Conner and Trey Benson is poised
for some fun competition. Still ahead.
Paul and Danny read and react to the
Cardinals free agency moves and what
they mean for the roster. More coming up
on Cardinals Bird Watch presented by
[music] SeatGeek.
The segment is presented by SeatGeek,
official primary ticketing partner of
the Arizona Cardinals. All right, Danny,
here we go. Head on a swivel, time for
read and react where we go back and
forth playing anchor and analyst. Only
one rule, all opinions your own, own
your opinion.
>> Here's the first read, Paul. Could
linebacker Jack Gibbons be the most
underappreciated free agent signing?
Absolutely. I mean, based on last year
when you lost Mack Wilson Sr., the
before and after of the Cardinals
defense, just how significant the loss
was your middle linebacker, to bring in
a guy who's had a ton of double-digit
tackle games in the last four years,
started the Super Bowl for New England,
absolutely.
>> You have great points. I'm not
disagreeing with you there. If Mack
Wilson Sr. is still the starting Mike
linebacker, still wearing the green dot,
this is more of a depth move. Now, the
fact that Wilson only played in eight
games because of injury last year and
his absence was felt does make this
Gibbons signing incredibly important.
However, I'm thinking more wide receiver
Devin Duvernay, the two-time Pro Bowler,
All-Pro returner, going to be a big dog
on special teams.
>> Okay, take the top off, serious speed, I
like it. Read, the addition of senior
defensive assistant Terron Austin to the
coaching staff will be a low-key,
valuable addition.
>> Wrong because it's a high key valuable
addition. He brings experience as a
three-time defensive coordinator. Austin
was once the Cardinals defensive backs
coach and actually received a lot of
praise online from Ring of Honor member
Adrian Wilson on his coaching style.
Austin was most recently with Pittsburgh
as their DC and in the four years he was
with the Steelers, that defense was
number one in takeaways, number six in
scoring defense. Having that information
and just that experience on the coaching
staff is incredibly valuable.
>> No, I like it a lot. Just working under
Mike Tomlin all those years, yeah. That
that's a bonus, no doubt. Okay, next
read or react. New safety Andrew Wingerd
reminds you of former Cardinals Dennis
Gardeck and or Pat Tillman. Okay, this
is a good one. This is a big debate
going on among the Red Sea.
Um I covered Pat Tillman. I'm old enough
to have done that. Little bit. I think
it's closer to Dennis Gardeck. Although
I see a lot of Kurt Cobain. As a guy who
actually saw Kurt Cobain [laughter] in
concert, I see some Kurt Cobain in
Andrew, the guy they called Dewey.
>> That flow is pretty stellar. They've got
that aura, more of laid-back, go with
the flow. But then when they step on the
football field, absolute dogs. I was not
around to cover Pat Tillman. I was
though with Dennis Gardeck. And both of
them are just complete menaces,
especially on special teams. They both
played in Jacksonville together. I feel
like it might take some of the the
people in the locker room a minute to
realize, "Oh, that's not Dennis
Gardeck." Hey, I did. When Jacksonville
played here, it took me a moment. I'm
like, "Wait, that's either Gardeck lost
40 lb or All right, next one. Here we
go. Read. New left guard Isaac Seumalo
played on the Eagles O-line when they
used the tush push. He says he's going
to suggest to coach LaFleur the
Cardinals use the tush push. React.
>> Why not? If you can get it to work,
that's why so many people were against
the tush push was because the Eagles
were seemingly the only team who could
consistently pull it off. You got a 6'4
quarterback in Jacoby Brissett. So the
Cardinals can make that work, I'm all
for it. If it works, go for it. As long
as it's legal. Because when it does
work, when they have it dialed in like
the Eagles do, it's dang near
unstoppable. So why not feed it to
Seattle and the Rams and the 49ers,
right? I'm all for it. Okay, that is
read and react. By the way, opportunity
knocks right around the corner.
Cardinals Bird Watch continues in a
moment. Presented by SeatGeek. This
segment is sponsored by Desert Financial
Credit Union, official banking partner
of the Arizona Cardinals. You did great
you did it. Same thing last time.
Yes, yes, yes. Close. You saw that
though? You saw that? That was so close.
We're here at State Farm Stadium, home
of the Arizona Cardinals. Here for the
STEM Combine, giving back to the kids,
having a great time. I'm giving them
some tips, you know, about football and
you know, just knowledge about life in
general.
Honeywell Aerospace [music] has this big
initiative to help develop the next
generation of scientists and engineers.
>> [music]
>> Historically, there's a stigma against
math and science and all this stuff. And
like [music] showing the kids how fun it
could be.
>> Oh, broad jump?
Wait, which side do I start it? Avnet's
thrilled to be a part of the STEM
Combine. [music] Our headquarters is
right here in Arizona. So partnering
with the Arizona Cardinals to [music]
bring this STEM event to all these kids
in Arizona is just incredible to us.
It's interesting to challenge your mind
and use collaborative efforts to, you
know, create really cool things. Like
these games are really exciting, but
you're also able to learn while having
fun. I think that's really cool.
Whatever you want to be in life,
whatever you choose to accomplish, as
long as you set your your mind and set
your goal to be that, I feel like they
can do it and accomplish anything in the
world. That's a win. It's the
off-season, but we're going to put the
STEM Combine event in the win column,
Paul.
>> No doubt about that. Look, we both had
the pleasure of hosting those events,
right? It's great to see they put the
fun in the classroom. Plus all the flag
football initiatives the Cardinals have
launched. I mean, you're keeping kids
off their phones, keeping them busy. It
is all good all around.
>> More than one way to win. Including on
the football field, including special
teams. An area the Cardinals recently
addressed by signing two-time Pro Bowl
returner wide receiver Devin Duvernay.
Last season, Paul, he was top three in
the league in total return yards.
>> Yeah, he returned kicks, he returned
punts for the Bears. He's going to
compete for wide receiver three with
Kendrick Bourne. Now, speaking of
Bourne, you might recognize the last
name, right? Part of a movie franchise.
So we had to ask Kendrick Bourne or
Jason Bourne?
I looked it up. There are There are five
films. Have you seen all five films?
>> I I might have seen three. Okay. I got I
got to I don't know what I'm missing. So
I haven't watched them in like
in order. I've just like randomly
>> So even the last name compared didn't
compel you to watch all five. No, you're
a busy guy. Okay, all right.
>> [laughter]
>> I need to. Well, you know, Matt Damon's
old. He's like almost as old as me. So I
mean, you know, they need a new Bourne.
I mean, you know, when you're done
playing, you could be the next Bourne.
So it's actually funny. So I have before
this before I came out here, I went to
did a NFL entertainment summit with the
NFL. It was like the trip. We went to
Hollywood. And I was acting, bro. And I
was like it was the toughest thing I've
kind of ever done. It took like real
work. So thinking about him,
I'm like, he might have more skills than
me.
>> [laughter]
>> He might have more skills cuz that
acting stuff, like football is easy. I
can go out there, that's what I do.
Acting, you have to like turn it on. So
uh but he got some skills, but I'm I'm
very talented, too. So I don't want to
belittle myself, but I love those
movies. I get those jokes all the time
and that like that name. Cuz people be
like, "Oh, you spell it B O R N?" I'll
be like, "No, I'm Bourne Supremacy."
[laughter]
Good luck trying to match Kendrick
Bourne's energy. Yet another great story
on Cover Two with you and Craig about
when the Niners and Cards faced off last
season.
>> Yeah, there was the second game, Michael
Wilson's breakout game. 18 targets, 15
catches for a buck 85. And then it was
after the game. In fact, we'll let
Kendrick take it from there.
>> Michael, I just met him last game or the
last game we played him when he went for
200 yards.
I was like, man, this guy is He had 18
targets, 15 catches.
>> Balling. I was like, bro, who is this
guy? So I didn't really know about
Michael at first. And I had to go up to
him after the game. Like, yeah, I just
felt it in my spirit to go talk to him.
I was like, "Hey, man, you're a baller.
I don't I don't know who you are, but
hey, I'm Kendrick, man. Nice to meet
you." Coming up, new additions, new
opportunities. And Danny Sorensen
connects the dots. You won't want to
miss it. Cardinals Bird Watch continues
after this. Presented by SeatGeek.
Welcome back to Cardinals Bird Watch.
Presented by SeatGeek. This segment is
presented by AM PM. All right. So with
free agency, you get a whole new wave of
players, right? New attitudes. Roy Lopez
said he could even sense a bit of a new
hunger in the hallways. And with a new
head coach, you know every player has
something to prove. In fact, oh, wait a
minute. There's that knock again. Danny,
you're back?
Paul, I don't know what you heard, but
opportunity does not stop knocking just
because it's the off-season. Especially
with these new faces on offense,
starting with quarterback Gardner
Minshew. Let's be clear from the jump.
Minshew comes in as a backup
quarterback, a role he's had in his last
few stops. He's been in the league for
seven years. He's got 47 starts under
his belt, a Pro Bowl, and almost 70
touchdowns. Having an experienced backup
quarterback who is poised and calm under
pressure while making smart decisions is
important. That was seen last year in
having Jacoby Brissett step up. That's
what the Cardinals now have in Minshew.
Regardless of whether the Cardinals do
or don't draft a quarterback next month
in April, the Cardinals now have a
trusted backup in Minshew that if he has
to step up, they feel good about what he
can provide them. Running back Tyler
Allgeier has the opportunity to not just
be a one-two punch with James Conner,
but to also do more. Conner is coming
off that gnarly ankle injury that
sidelined him for a majority of last
season. If Conner is healthy, that's
great. If he's not as healthy to start
the season or is in a more limited
capacity role, Allgeier has the
opportunity to step up. The 5'10 220
running back is a human wrecking ball.
As the featured back his rookie year in
Atlanta, he surpassed 1,000 rushing
yards. 13 [music] of his 18 career
rushing touchdowns have come inside the
10. And he starts his tenure as an
Arizona Cardinal without a single career
fumble. Running back Trey Benson enters
year three and has a lot to prove about
staying healthy and making the most of
his opportunities.
>> [music]
>> That room with those three is going to
provide some fun healthy competition
throughout the off-season and into
training camp. Wide receiver Kendrick
Bourne brings the energy. And as a
receiver, loves to do the dirty work,
blocking, working the middle of the
field. The nine-year vet doesn't have a
ton of special teams experience. His
opportunity is to be the number three
wideout behind Marvin Harrison Jr. and
Michael Wilson. That trust is already
there with Bourne and this coaching
staff, especially with head coach Mike
LaFleur. LaFleur was once upon a time
Bourne's position coach when the two
were in San Francisco a couple years
ago. Doesn't have a ton of career
receptions, although he has an average
of 13 yards per catch. So when the ball
comes Bourne's way, he makes the most of
it. Offensive lineman Isaac Seumalo has
the most interesting [music] opportunity
cuz he's the only one who comes in as a
projected starter on the offensive line.
He's projected to be the starting left
guard between Paris Johnson Jr. and
Yodny Cajuste. He's got a decades worth
of experience and versatility having
played on both sides of the line. The
Cardinals were bottom of the league in
the run game and in sacks allowed last
year. This is an area they're looking to
beef up. Paul, that's noticeable with
some of the moves. Not to mention
Seumalo has some clean football under
his belt. Not a single penalty called
against him last year with Pittsburgh.
>> Yeah, that's remarkable. He's played
some of his best ball the last couple
years. Of course, he went against Cam
Heyward every day in practice. You talk
about iron sharpening iron. You talk
about a Cardinals team that had the
fewest rushing attempts in the NFL last
year because of all the injuries, the
O-line, running back room. [music] Not
going to happen this year, right? I
mean, if the Cardinals beat teams, I
have a feeling they're going to beat
them up in the run game. Look at the
landscape of the NFC West. The Cardinals
have to have a better run game. That is
how you control the game, control the
line of scrimmage, and wear down a
defense. That's the goal they want to
get to. And these moves make it clear
that's what they're trying to
accomplish.
>> Bring the heat. Sort of like our phones
this week have said extreme heat warning
in March. So stay cool, Red Sea. We'll
see you next week.